GISELE LIMA

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

Curiosity about how things are made and gratification in solving problems led me to become a Production Engineer 13 years ago.

Today, those same drivers, plus my passion for continuous learning, directed me to shift my career and become a Software Developer.

Dedicating some of my personal time to support causes that are close to my heart and that make a positive impact in the community are also what keep me motivated in life.

On top of all that, I'm a scuba diver, a vegan foodie and an outdoor lover.

KEY PROJECTS

DESPERATE HOUSEWARES APP

https://www.desperate-housewares.com/

- E-commerce with the purpose of giving online visibility to local opshops, built as part of a teamwork project using the MERN stack
- My responsibility was focused on Express, Cloudinary, MongoDB and Mongoose implementation while developing unit and integration tests with Jest

VEGME APP

https://vegme-app.herokuapp.com/

- Two-sided marketplace application where users are customers looking for delivery of vegan meals and restaurants offering their meal options for this growing niche market
- Built with Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Cloudinary and Bootstrap
- Features: CRUD operations, user authentication and authorisation, image handling with CDN, shopping cart and payment gateway

ALTERNATIVE PAYROLL APP

https://github.com/limagisele/terminal-app.git

- Ruby terminal app developed as a backup payroll system where employees can enter their timesheets and managers can generate payroll reports
- Features: user authentication, CRUD functionalities, data validation, csv file generation for report, TDD using RSpec



0478 961 861



limagisele05@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/limagisele



github.com/limagisele



https://giselelima.netlify.app/



Bonbeach, Vic 3196

SKILLS

- Adaptability
- Analytical Thinking
- Empathy
- Project Management
- · Problem-solving
- Change Management
- Languages: Ruby, JavaScript
- Framework: Rails, React, Express.js
- Database: PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- **Deployment:** Heroku, Netlify

EDUCATION

2022 - FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP

Coder Academy

2014 - MASTER OF PRODUCTION ENGINEERING

Universidade Federal de Pernambuco

2008 - BACHELOR OF PRODUCTION ENGINEERING

Universidade Federal de Pernambuco

GISELE LIMA

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

PREVIOUS EMPLOYMENT

PRODUCTION MANAGER

Coca-Cola Europacific Partners

2021 - 2022

- Managed team of 3 team managers, 1 scheduler and 23 operators
- Eliminated reoccurrence of customer's complaint for packaging and improved customer's satisfaction by personally visiting their automated warehouse to assess the issue, then developing and implementing an adequate improvement plan
- Improved department's Quality KPIs by 25%, through encouraging team's ownership of their results, addressing their roadblocks and celebrating their wins

LINE MANAGER

Nestle

2016 - 2021

- Identified business improvement opportunities in accordance to yearly Business Plan and negotiated targets, resources and deadlines with key stakeholders
- Led improvement project that resulted in 38% increase of production line's output and saving of \$113k/year in material cost through data analysis, communication with end-users and technical experts, and coaching team members on new implemented tools
- Led production project responsible for transferring manufacturing lines from NSW to Vic and ensured essential technical skills were captured and transferred to the new team, allowing a successful start-up of all lines

CERTIFICATION

JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPMENT

General Assembly (In Progress)

LEAN SIX SIGMA GREEN BELT

Melbourne University **2019**

VOLUNTEERING

VOLUNTEER TUTOR

Melbourne AMEP

May 2021 - Current

- Support migrants to settle in Australia in accordance to their needs
- Mentor female engineers seeking their first job in Australia

KENNEL ASSISTANT

Australian Animal Protection Society **Jun 2022 - Current**

- Provide enrichment for the dogs
- · Cleaning and feeding duties
- Dog walking